IBRAHIM ALKAYSSI

Information Technology - State Employee

IBRAHIM.ALKAYSSI@EDD.CA.GOV

4990 HARSTON WAY, ANTELOPE, CA 95843 - (916) 770-6648 -

IBRAHIMALKAYSSI@YAHOO.COM

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Knowledgeable Information Technology Specialist. Capable of setting up and optimizing workstations, assisting users, and engaging with improvement implementation in diverse areas. Able to work quickly and patiently with users in remote and desk-side environments, to resolve issues successfully and provide guidance.

SKILLS

- Setting up computer workstations, including peripheral devices.
- Remote access operation to assist employees.
- Ensuring security and privacy of networks and computers.
- Identifying equipment shortages and placing orders for more.
- Organizing and scheduling upgrades and maintenance so employees continue working without interruptions.
- Assisting with technical questions from users.

WORK HISTORY

Employment Development Department

August 2020 to Current

Employment Program Representative

Sacramento, California

- Assist claimants with their online accounts, unlock or send rest password links as needed.
- Determine eligibility for UI benefits in accordance with laws, regulations, and policies using state programs.
- · Interpret and apply laws, policies, and precedent to decisions consistently to individual cases
- Conduct Unemployment Insurance (UI) eligibility determinations.

TriWest Health Care alliance

November 2015 to June 2020

Information Technology Specialist

Elk Grove, CA

- Managed user profiles, security access and shared file structures.
- Kept employees informed about issue resolution progress and provided updated estimated times of resolution on daily basis.
- Assisted employees with technical issues via Email, Live-chat, and Telephone.
- Researched, documented, and escalated support cases to higher levels of support when unable to resolve issues using available resources.
- Managed IT setup and service requests for local and remote users.

Apple Inc

February 2011 to Nov 2015

Test Technician

Sacramento, CA

- Informed Customers of their options when a system was deemed ineffective to repair due to age of device, source of problem, manufacturer fault and estimated resolution time.
- Data entry of incoming and outgoing products and parts.
- Documenting operating status of products after running a multitude of testing stages.
- Testing a variety of Apple products such as IPhones, IPads, and MacBooks.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

COMMUNICATIONS TECHNOLOGIES - ASSOCIATE OF SCIENCE, SIERRA COLLEGE | COMPTIA A +